Home Rule Committee 055
People's Archive, MLK Library
Home Rule Committee Collection
1939-1961
People's Archive, MLK Library
Home Rule Committee
055
1 Boxes
0.5 Linear feet
Biographical / Historical
In 1953 Washington, D.C. residents established the Home Rule Committee to flex their social influence into greater attention to home rule. Members included Democratic political activist Daisy Harriman, museum director Duncan Phillips, businessman Frank Jelleff, and Washington Post publisher Phillip Graham. Members organized dinners and parties; testified in Congress; wrote letters to the editors; picketed; and lobbied in support of home rule for the District.
Custodial History
The materials were removed from the Washingtoniana Vertical File Collection to ensure their preservation. Annabel Bogdonoff, former secretary to the board of directors of the Home Rule Committee, Arthur Newmeyer, and Gary Abramson donated the materials to the DC Public Library.
Related Materials
Washingtoniana Vertical Files Artificial and Ephemera Collection (060) Statehood Commission Collection (048) Julius Hobson Collection (001) Self Determination for D.C. National Coalition Collection (003) Harry S. Wender Collection (009) League of Women Voters of D.C. Collection (033) Oral History Collections 13 and 18
Scope and Contents
The materials include meeting minutes; correspondence; congressional testimony; by-laws; pamphlets; a history of the Home Rule Committee; political pins and stickers; and clippings. Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Politics and government; Home rule -- Washington (D.C.); Suffrage; Ephemera; Organizational Records; Correspondence; Minutes (Records)
- Series 1
  - Annabel Bogdonoff materials, 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1949-1953, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Congressional testimony and related documents, 1949-1951, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial statements, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting minutes, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "We Want to Vote" pendant, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Washington Wants to Vote" stickers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)